Guide to the Emmons Family Papers 1779-1991 (Bulk 1779-1842) MS 014 MS 014 MS 014
Cornwall Historical Society
Emmons Family Papers
1779-1991
, (Bulk 1779-1842)
Cornwall Historical Society
Emmons, Asa (1756- )
MS 014
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
This collection contains items relating to the Emmons family that lived in Cornwall, CT.
Provenance
The collection was donated to the Cornwall Historical Society in 1991 by homeowners who found them within the house they had purchased.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The majority of the documents are deeds that belonged to Asa Emmons and together they document his gradual accumulation of land in Cornwall during his life. Asa, Mary, and Simeon were all children of Woodruff Emmons (1718-1793), who first brought the family to Cornwall, and became well known in the area for keeping an inn. Luther Emmons’ exact relation to the family is unknown, but it is likely that he was a grandson of Woodruff.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains items relating to the Emmons family, specifically Asa Emmons (1756-unknown), Luther Emmons, Mary Emmons, and Simeon Emmons (1747-1805). The material consists mostly of deeds.
Arrangement
The folders are organized by family member then in alphabetical order.
The collection is grouped into 3 series
I. Asa Emmons
II. Emmons Family
III. Provenance
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Cornwall (Conn.); Deeds; Emmons, Asa (1756- ); Emmons, Woodruff (1718-1793); Emmons, Simeon (1747-1805)
- Asa Emmons
  - Deeds of Asa Emmons, 1779-1818; , undated (Box 1, Folder 1'-20)
  - Pages from Asa Emmons day book, 1806-1806 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Supplement to the last will and testament of Asa Emmons, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Other Emmons Family Members
  - Bond between Earl Johnson and Luther Emmons, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Deed between John R. Harrison and Mary Emmons, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Deed between Benjamin Gold and Samuel Hopkins and Simeon Emmons, 1811 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Provenance
  - Folder with note on collection’s provenance, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter from the Cornwall Historical Society to "Tom" James regarding donation of the collection, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)